Education College Records (Preliminary Inventory) 1911-1958
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections (MASC)
Education College Records (Preliminary Inventory)
1911-1958
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections (MASC) Holland and Terrell Libraries Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Archives 13
34 linear feet
Includes general office records, correspondence, budgets, course materials, and conference proceedings, 1911-1958; Summer Session Records, Class Grade Records Books and In Service Teacher Preparation (ISTP) Records.
The early history of Washington State University's College of Education, as revealed in these records, was closely bound to the career of Dean Alfred Alexander Cleveland (b.1876) and the development of primary and secondary education within Washington State. Born in Oregon, Cleveland acquired the Ph.D. in psychology from Clark University in 1906. In 1907 A.. A. Cleveland joined the faculty of the, then, state College of Washington as Assistant Professor of Psychology. Between 1908 and 1910 he first became full professor and then temporary head of the education department. In those times education and psychology were parts of the same department. During the 1917 reorganization WSU was divided into five colleges and four schools. Cleveland's responsibilities then included the deanship of the School of Education and directorship of the annual Summer Session. The records indicate the important role the Summer Session played in enlarging the formal training of primary and secondary teacher in the State of Washington.
Thus from the early years Dean Cleveland was to play an important role in developing education and psychology at WSU. Often in those years he was the only full-time teacher in the department of education. In addition, he served on many statewide educational committees and groups. His students were potent forces within the State of Washington calling for increased attention to quality education for all and adequate teacher preparation. Cleveland served as Dean of the School of Education until his retirement early in 1941.
Dean Cleveland's replacement, J. Murry Lee, came to WSU in January 1941 directly from the faculty of the University of Wisconsin where he had been and active scholar, teacher, and consultant to educational groups. He held the Ph.D. in Education from Columbia University and had experience as a school principal in Los Angeles.
Upon arrival at WSU he proceeded to continue many of Dean Cleveland's policies but he also moved rapidly to help meet the impending war needs of the United States. Lee's first years at WSU were interrupted when he was called to serve in the U. S. Navy from 1943 to 1945. Cleveland temporarily resumed his duties as dean of the School of Education during Lee's absence. However, to ease Cleveland's administrative burden Lee removed the direction of the Summer Session from the Dean's Office. He placed fellow faculty member L. L. Chisholm in temporary charge of the Summer Session. The records show that this new situation produced great strain between the temporary Dean and the temporary Director of the Summer Session.
Upon Lee's return direction of the Summer Session reverted back to the Dean's Office. In addition, Lee began to take up the problems of post-war American education. For example, the program of inservice teacher Preparation was expanded to meet the new demands of returning veterans and the predicted post-war "baby boom." The records show that the WSU College of education actively worked to secure the same objectives it had always sought--quality education for all Washington State citizens through high quality teacher preparation.
The records of the College of Education comprise five series. The first series is arranged chronologically (there are several missing years) and alphabetically within each year. Some years in this series are designated by a year followed by "A-Z" This indicates that within that year the file folders have the heading 'A', 'B',etc. Other years are designated because they were separated from the major records series, on receipt.
The Collection is open for research use.
Washington State University. College of Education--Archives; State College of Washington. College of Education.; Washington State University. College of Education--Records and correspondence
Teachers--Training of--Washington (State)--Archival resources
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities
- General Office Records, including correspondence, budgets, course materials, and conference proceedings, 1911-1958; 1
  - Cleveland Correspondence. A-V 1912 (Box 1)
  - A-Z 1912 (Box 1)
  - A-Z no date (Box 1)
  - Inventory 1914 (Box 1)
  - A 1918 (Box 1)
  - Ba-Be 1918 (Box 1)
  - Bi-Bri 1918 (Box 1)
  - Bro-By 1918 (Box 1)
  - Ca-Cl 1918 (Box 1)
  - Co-Cy 1918 (Box 1)
  - D 1918 (Box 1)
  - E 1918 (Box 1)
  - F 1918 (Box 1)
  - Ga-Gl 1918 (Box 1)
  - Go-Gy 1918 (Box 1)
  - Ha-Hd 1918 (Box 1)
  - He-Hn 1918 (Box 1)
  - Ho-Hz 1918 (Box 1)
  - Ma-Md 1918 (Box 1)
  - Me-Mn 1918 (Box 1)
  - Mo-Mz 1918 (Box 1)
  - N 1918 (Box 1)
  - O 1918 (Box 1)
  - Pa-Ph 1918 (Box 1)
  - Pi-Pz 1918 (Box 1)
  - Ra-Rn 1918 (Box 1)
  - Ro-Rz 1918 (Box 1)
  - Sa-Sd 1918 (Box 1)
  - Se-Sm 1918 (Box 1)
  - Sn-Sth 1918 (Box 1)
  - Sti-Sz 1918 (Box 1)
  - Examination Questions 1916-1918 (Box 1)
  - Sti-Sz 1920 (Box 1)
  - 20 File (Box 2)
  - Seattle Speech (Box 2)
  - Curriculum Journal Bibliography (Box 2)
  - Summer Session Advisory Committee (Box 2)
  - Payroll (Summer Session 1941) ’39-40 (Box 2)
  - Extension Conference (Box 2)
  - Summer Session 1941 Request to President (Box 2)
  - Ag Vocational Conference (Box 2)
  - Summer Session 1941-1942 (Box 2)
  - 1942 Summer Session Evergreen (Box 2)
  - Publicity and Advertising Summer Session ‘42 (Box 2)
  - Inter-America Relations Summer Session ‘42 (Box 2)
  - Summer Session Institute for Pastors - Summer Session ‘42 (Box 2)
  - Agricultural Extension Conference Summer Session ‘42 (Box 2)
  - Janitorial Conference Summer Session 42 (Box 2)
  - Summer Session Possibilities (Box 2)
  - Summer Session Announcements from other Institutions (Box 2)
  - Ideas Summer Session ‘42 (Box 2)
  - Approved Courses for Administrators Credentials (Box 2)
  - Summer Session PLans: Applicants (Box 2)
  - Schedule, 2nd Sem. 1933-34 (Box 2)
  - Schedule 1st Semester 1935-36 (Box 2)
  - Schedule, 2nd Sem. 1935-36 (Box 2)
  - Summer Session Schedule (1940) (Box 2)
  - Schedule 1st Semester 1936-1937 (Box 2)
  - Schedule 2nd Semester II – 1936-37 (Box 2)
  - Schedule – I – 1937-38 (Box 2)
  - Schedule II – 1937-38 (Box 2)
  - Schedule I – 1938-39 (Box 2)
  - Schedule II – 1938-39 (Box 2)
  - Schedule I – 1939-40 (Box 2)
  - Schedule II – 1939-40 (Box 2)
  - Financial Annual Budget 1919-1939 (Box 2)
  - Appointments Committee, 1913 (Box 3)
  - Appointments Committee, 1913 (Box 3)
  - A-J (Box 3)
  - L-Z (Box 3)
  - A-Z 1924 (Box 3)
  - Sn-W 1923 (Box 3)
  - A-Lz 1926 (Box 3)
  - A-H 1926 (Box 3)
  - Pres. E.O. Holland 1926 (Box 3)
  - J-L 1926 (Box 3)
  - Wash. Ed. Assoc. Com. on Professional Ethics (Box 3)
  - Mr. Barnard, Registrar 1927 (Box 3)
  - B-C 1927 (Box 3)
  - College Teaching 1927 (Box 3)
  - D-H 1927 (Box 3)
  - Pres. E.O. Holland 1927 (Box 3)
  - I-P 1927 (Box 3)
  - Phi Kappa Phi (Box 3)
  - Recommendations 1927 (Box 3)
  - R 1927 (Box 3)
  - S.C. Roberts 1927 (Box 3)
  - S 1927 (Box 3)
  - Dr. C.W. Stone (Box 3)
  - T-W 1927 (Box 3)
  - A-Z 1928-1931 (Box 3)
  - A-Z 1929-31 (Box 3)
  - A-Y 1932 (Box 4)
  - Summer Session Follow Up Letters (no date) (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (bound with string) (Box 4)
  - Accountant: Krugel Hix 1933 (Box 4)
  - Al 1932 (Box 4)
  - Applications 1933 (Box 4)
  - Ba-Bh 2 1933 (Box 4)
  - Barnard-Registrar 1933 (Box 4)
  - Bi-Brn 3 1933 (Box 4)
  - Bro-Bz 4 1933 (Box 4)
  - Ca-Cn 5 1933 (Box 4)
  - Cadet Teachers 1933 (Box 4)
  - Catalog Material 1933 (Box 4)
  - Chamber of Commerce 1933 (Box 4)
  - Co-Cz 6 1933 (Box 4)
  - D 7 1933 (Box 4)
  - Departmental 1933 (Box 4)
  - E 8 1933 (Box 5)
  - F 9 1933 (Box 5)
  - Financial Statements 1928-1933 (Box 5)
  - Faculty Notices 1933 (Box 5)
  - Fuller, Henry H – Supervisor of Cadet Teaching in Spokane 1933 (Box 5)
  - Ga-Gn 10 1933 (Box 5)
  - Go-Gz 11 1933 (Box 5)
  - Ha-Hd 12 1933 (Box 5)
  - Ho-Hz 14 1933 (Box 5)
  - I 15 1933 (Box 5)
  - J 16 1933 (Box 5)
  - K 17 1933 (Box 5)
  - KWSC 19 1933 (Box 5)
  - La-Lh 18 1933 (Box 5)
  - Li-Lz 19 1933 (Box 5)
  - Library: Foote W.W. to others 1933 (Box 5)
  - He-Hn 13 1933 (Box 5)
  - Holland, President E.O. 1933 (Box 5)
  - Ma-Md 20 1933 (Box 5)
  - Me-Mn 21 1933 (Box 5)
  - Mo-Mz 22 1933 (Box 5)
  - N 23 1933 (Box 5)
  - O 24 1933 (Box 5)
  - Pa-Ph 24 1933 (Box 5)
  - Pickett-Graduate School 1933 (Box 5)
  - Phi Delta Kappa 1933 (Box 5)
  - Pi-Pz 26 1933 (Box 5)
  - Q 27 1933 (Box 5)
  - Ra-Rn 28 1933 (Box 5)
  - Recommendations 1933 (Box 5)
  - Sa-Z (no date) (Box 5)
  - Absences July 1, 5, 8 (1933) (Box 5)
  - Summer Session Advertising 1933 (Box 5)
  - Assembly Programs (Box 5)
  - Summer Session Advisory Council 1933 (Box 5)
  - Summer Session Applications 1933 A-Z (Box 5)
  - S.S Bulletins 1933 (Box 5)
  - Summer Session 1933 (Box 5)
  - Summer Session Classes (Box 5)
  - Summer Session Financial 1933 (Box 5)
  - Furnished Rooms and Appartments (Box 5)
  - Summer Session Lectures and Entertainment 1933 (Box 5)
  - Summer Session Mailing List 1933 (Box 5)
  - Summer Session Preliminary Announcement 1933 (Box 5)
  - Summer Session Schedule (Box 5)
  - Cleveland 1934 (Box 5)
  - A-Z 1934 (Box 5)
  - A-Z 1935 (Box 6)
  - Summer Session 1936 (Box 6)
  - Summer Session Committee Minutes (Box 6)
  - Recommendations 1935 (Box 6)
  - A-Z 1936 (Box 6)
  - Statute of Dept. of Ed. 1936 (Box 6)
  - Certification 1936 (Box 6)
  - Student Prospects Recommended for Teacher Training, 1935 (Box 6)
  - J-Z (no date) (Box 6)
  - Aiken (Box 6)
  - Accountant Krugel, Hix, Jacobs, Broch, ect. (Box 6)
  - Barnard, F.T. Registrar (Box 6)
  - Departmental 1936 (Box 6)
  - Educational Conference 1936 (Box 6)
  - Fuller, Dr. H.H. 1936 (Box 6)
  - Holland, Pres. E.O. (Box 6)
  - Pickett, Dean F.L. Graduate School (Box 6)
  - Recommendations 1936 (Box 6)
  - State Dept. of Education 1936 (Box 6)
  - B-D 1937 (Box 6)
  - Barnard, F.T. (Registrar) (Box 6)
  - Catalogue 1937 (Box 6)
  - Departmental (Box 6)
  - Demonstration School 1937 (Box 6)
  - General College Extension (Box 6)
  - President Holland (Box 6)
  - Library (Box 6)
  - N.Y.A. 1937 (Box 6)
  - Pickett, Dean F.L. (Box 6)
  - Pictures (Box 6)
  - Planning Council (Box 6)
  - Recommendations (Box 6)
  - Rural Pastors 1937 (Box 6)
  - State Dept. of Education (Box 6)
  - Vocational Education (Box 6)
  - Whiffen (Correspondence) (Box 6)
  - Whiffen (Financial Statements) (Box 6)
  - Pickett, Dean F.L. 1938 (Box 6)
  - State Dept. of Education 1938 (Box 6)
  - Graduates in Agriculture (Box 6)
  - State Board of Ed. 1938 (Box 6)
  - Teacher Training Plan 1938 (Box 6)
  - Biennial Budget 1939 – Education and Summer Session (Box 6)
  - Annual Budget 1939-40 – Education and Summer Session (Box 6)
  - Educational Conference (Box 6)
  - Recommendations of WSC Students 1938 (Box 6)
  - Planning Council 1938 (Box 6)
  - Vocational Education 1938 (Box 6)
  - Dean W.L. Uhl 1938 (Box 6)
  - President Holland 1938 (Box 6)
  - KWSC Dean Phillips 1938-39 (Box 6)
  - Manual Arts Teachers 1938 (Box 6)
  - Cleveland 1938 (Box 6)
  - Breckner, Elmer L. 1938-39 (Box 6)
  - State Department of California (Box 6)
  - Vocational Education – Agricultural Short Course 1940 (Box 7)
  - Fuller, H.H. 1940 (Box 7)
  - Applications 1940 (Box 7)
  - Barnard F.T. 1940 (Box 7)
  - Business Office 1940 (Box 7)
  - Brown, WM. H. 1940 (Box 7)
  - Brown, WM. H. 1942 (Box 7)
  - Aiken, N.J. 1940 (Box 7)
  - Committee on Administrative Credentials 1940 (Box 7)
  - Conference on Higher Edu. 1940 (Box 7)
  - Summer Session 1940 (Box 7)
  - Whiffen, U.G. 1940 (Box 7)
  - Whiffen (Financial) 1939-40 (Box 7)
  - State Dept. Education 1940 (Box 7)
  - Recommendations 1940-41 (Box 7)
  - Graduate School 1940 (Box 7)
  - Holland, E.O. 1940 (Box 7)
  - Annual Report of Staff Members July 1940 (Box 7)
  - Recommendations 1941 (Box 7)
  - Special Examination – System – Ohio State U. 1940-41 (Box 7)
  - Legislature Material 1941 (Box 7)
  - Important People 1941 (Box 7)
  - KWSC 1940-41 (Box 7)
  - Holland, E.O. 1941 (Box 7)
  - HS Visitations for Fall 1941 (Box 7)
  - Graduate School 1941 (Box 7)
  - Graduate Studies Committee 1941 (Box 7)
  - Future Teachers Material - NEA (No Year) (Box 7)
  - Fuller, H.H. 1941 (Box 7)
  - Ethics Comm. 1941 (Box 7)
  - Department Library List (No Year) (Box 7)
  - Departmental 1940-41 (Box 7)
  - Conference Programs (No Year) (Box 7)
  - Letters of Congratulations on Deanship 1941 (Box 7)
  - Committee on Administrative Credentials 1941 (Box 7)
  - College Publications 1941 (Box 7)
  - Commercial Education 1942 (Box 7)
  - Barnard, F.T. 1941 (Box 7)
  - 4-H Club Questionnaire (No Year) (Box 7)
  - Advisor’s Report to Coordinator 1941 (Box 7)
  - The Association of Deans and Directors of Summer Sessions Twenty-Forth Annual Meeting Oct 17-18, 1941 (Box 7)
  - Summary of Reports 1941 (Box 7)
  - Spokane Workshop Directory Summer 1941 (Box 7)
  - Summer Workshop – 1941 – Group Activities and Reports (Box 7)
  - Personal Report to Coordinator 1941 (Box 7)
  - Masters Programs 1941 (Box 7)
  - Oregon Trip 1941 (Box 7)
  - Aiken, N.J. 1941 (Box 7)
  - State Dept. of Education 1941 (Box 7)
  - Whiffen, U.G. (Financial) 1941 (Box 7)
  - Workshop – Spokane – Summer Session 1941 (Box 7)
  - Janitorial School – Summer Session 1941 (Box 7)
  - Aviation Course 1942 (Box 7)
  - Barnard, F.T. 1942 (Box 7)
  - Faculty Advisory Board 1942 (Box 7)
  - Curriculum Library 1942 (Box 7)
  - Departmental 1942 (Box 7)
  - Doctors Degree 1942 – Applications and Letters indicating Interest (Box 7)
  - Elementary School Social Studies 1942 (Box 7)
  - Graduate School 1942 (Box 7)
  - Graduate Studies Committee 1942 (Box 7)
  - High School Senior Bulletin 1942 (Box 7)
  - Holland, E.O. 1942 (Box 7)
  - Meetings Attended 1942 (Box 7)
  - Recommendations 1942 (Box 7)
  - Reorganization of School Districts 1942 (Box 7)
  - Research Studies – 1942 – Letters, Comments, Mailing List 1942 (Box 7)
  - State Board Meeting Minutes 1942 (Box 7)
  - State Board 1942 (Box 7)
  - 1942 State Board (Box 7)
  - State Department of Education 1942 (Box 7)
  - Vocational Educ. For War Workers 1942 (Box 7)
  - U.G. Whiffen – Correspondence 1942 (Box 7)
  - U.G. Whiffen – Financial – 1942 (Box 7)
  - Holland, E.O. -1942- President of W.S.C. (Box 7)
  - U.G. Whiffen – Correspondence (No Year) (Box 7)
  - Morale Studies 1942 (Box 7)
  - Morale Studies Test Applications 1942 (Box 7)
  - Vocational Education (War Workers) 1942 (Box 7)
  - Certification Committee 1941-42 (Box 7)
  - Summer School Departmental Costs 1942 (Box 7)
  - Lee 1940 (Box 7)
  - Conference Attended 1940-1941 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous 1942 (Box 8)
  - Boy Scouts – Air Scouts 1943 (Box 8)
  - Budget April 1943-March 1944 (Box 8)
  - Budget for 1942-1943 (Box 8)
  - Budget Biennium 1943-1945 Items Needed (Box 8)
  - Ca-Cn 5 1943 (Box 8)
  - Courses of Study (No Year) (Box 8)
  - Departmental – Reports by Staff (Box 8)
  - F 9 (No Year) (Box 8)
  - Educational Policies Commission 1943 (Box 8)
  - Fellowships 1943-1944 (Box 8)
  - Holland E.O. and Office Staff 1943 (Box 8)
  - Library 1943 (Box 8)
  - Li-Lz 19 1943 (Box 8)
  - Ma-Md 20 1943 (Box 8)
  - Northwest Society for Super and Corr. Development 1943 (Box 8)
  - Portland Trip – May 1943 (Box 8)
  - National Education Association 1943 (Box 8)
  - Vocational Education – H.Ec. – Agric – State Depart. 1944 (Box 8)
  - State Board 1943 (Box 8)
  - Washington High School Principals Association Meetings – Seattle (No Year) (Box 8)
  - N.J. Aiken 1942 (Box 8)
  - A 1 1942 (Box 8)
  - Ba-Bh 2 1942 (Box 8)
  - Bi-Brm 3 1942 (Box 8)
  - Bro-Bz 4 1942 (Box 8)
  - Ca-Cn 5 1942 (Box 8)
  - Co-Cz 6 1940 (Box 8)
  - D 7 1942 (Box 8)
  - E 8 1940 (Box 8)
  - F 9 1942 (Box 8)
  - Ga-Gn 10 1940 (Box 8)
  - Ha-Hd 12 1940 (Box 8)
  - He-Hn 13 (No Year) (Box 8)
  - Ho-Hz 14 1940 (Box 8)
  - He-Hn 13 1942 (Box 8)
  - I 15 1940 (Box 8)
  - J 16 1940 (Box 8)
  - K 17 1942 (Box 8)
  - La-Lh 18 1942 (Box 8)
  - Li-Lz 19 1941 (Box 8)
  - Library 1941 (Box 8)
  - Ma-Md 20 1942 (Box 8)
  - Me-Mn 21 1941 (Box 8)
  - Mo-Mz 22 1942 (Box 8)
  - N 23 1940 (Box 8)
  - O 24 1942 (Box 8)
  - Pa-Ph 25 1942 (Box 8)
  - Pi-Pz 26 1942 (Box 8)
  - Q 27 1940 (Box 8)
  - Ra-Rn 28 1942 (Box 8)
  - Ro-Rz 29 1940 (Box 8)
  - Sa-Sd 30 1940 (Box 8)
  - Se-Sm 31 1941 (Box 8)
  - Sn-Sth 32 1940 (Box 8)
  - Sti-Sz 33 1942 (Box 8)
  - T 34 1942 (Box 8)
  - V 36 1942 (Box 8)
  - Wa-Wg 37 1941 (Box 8)
  - X-Y 39 1942 (Box 8)
  - Recommendations 1943 (Box 8)
  - Summer Session Enrollment 1943 (Box 8)
  - Summer Session Conferences ‘43 (Box 8)
  - Summer Session Budget 1943 (Box 8)
  - Summer Session Advertisment – ‘43 (Box 8)
  - Summer Session Forms – Completed – 1943 (Box 8)
  - Summer Session Entertainment 1943 (Box 8)
  - Publishers Text 1943 (Box 8)
  - Summer Session 1943 – Catalogue (Box 8)
  - Home Economics – Summer Session 1943 (Box 8)
  - Summer Session Plans 1943 (Box 8)
  - Summer Session Library – 1943 (Box 8)
  - Prepflight Aeronautics Course – Enrollment Summer Session ‘43 (Box 8)
  - Faculty Applications, Offers etc – Summer Session ‘43 (Box 8)
  - Teaching Possibilities Summer Session ‘43 (Box 8)
  - Summer Session 1943 (Box 8)
  - Speech Material for 1942-‘43 (Box 8)
  - Visual Aids and Ed. Workshop 1945 (Box 8)
  - Reading Readiness Manual 1943 (Box 8)
  - Curriculum Bibliography 1942 (Box 9)
  - Summer Session 1947 (Box 9)
  - Catalogs 1946 (Box 9)
  - Summer School Enrollment 1946 (Box 9)
  - Summer School Payroll 1946 (Box 9)
  - Summer Session 1946 (Box 9)
  - Possibilities for 1947 – Summer Session (Box 9)
  - Summer Session Recreation Fund 1946 (Box 9)
  - Summer Session Prospective Students 1946 (Box 9)
  - Home Economics, Summer Session, 1945 (Box 9)
  - Summer Session 1946 (Box 9)
  - Summer Camp and Session 1946 (Box 9)
  - Curriculum and Catalog Comsn. 1946 (Box 9)
  - Curriculum and Cat. Com. 1947 (Box 9)
  - Applications – 1936 and 1938 (Box 9)
  - Applications for Assistantship 1936 – For Commercial Education (Box 9)
  - Applications – 1935 (Box 9)
  - Applications – Sch. Of Ed. 1943 (Box 9)
  - Applications – Summer Session 43 (Box 9)
  - Applications – School of Education 1942 (Box 9)
  - A 1 1944 (Box 9)
  - Research 1931 – Phi Delta Kappa (Box 9)
  - Z 40 1931 (Box 9)
  - Accrediting Standards for tea. Colleges 1943 (Box 9)
  - Aiken, N.J. – Placement Bureau 1944 (Box 9)
  - Barnard, F.T. – Register 1944 (Box 9)
  - Bi-Brn 3 1944 (Box 9)
  - Bibliographies for a Professional Library (No Year) (Box 9)
  - Bro-Bz 4 1944 (Box 9)
  - Budget – Biennial – Summer Session – School of Ed. 1943-1945 (Box 9)
  - Bursar’s Office – Hix. 1944 (Box 9)
  - Fuller, H.H. – Geiger 1944 (Box 9)
  - Ca-Cn 5 1944 (Box 9)
  - Clapp Questionnaire 1944 (Box 9)
  - Co-Cz 6 1944 (Box 9)
  - College and Departmental Publications 1944 (Box 9)
  - D 7 1944 (Box 9)
  - Departmental, Reports, Correspondence 1944 (Box 9)
  - E 8 1944 (Box 9)
  - Federal Surplus Properties 1944 (Box 9)
  - Faculty Notices 1944 (Box 9)
  - General College Extension – Jones 1944 (Box 9)
  - Holland, E.O. Office and Staff 1944 (Box 9)
  - I 15 1944 (Box 9)
  - J 16 1944 (Box 9)
  - La-Lh 18 1944 (Box 9)
  - Ma-Md 20 1944 (Box 9)
  - Mo-Mz 22 1944 (Box 9)
  - Core Curriculum (Box 10)
  - J Murray Lee Private Papers, SCW 1941-1951 (Box 10)
  - J Murray Lee Correspondence, SCW 1941-1947 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, SCW 1941- (Box 10)
  - Dept of Education Budget, 1945-1946 (Box 10)
  - Vocational Education in Washington State (Box 10)
  - President's Committee Report, March 1945 (Box 10)
  - Graduate Studies Documents, Schol of Education, 1941-1948 (Box 10)
  - Misc. Educational Documents, 1942-1948 (Box 10)
  - Education 145x, Course Materials (Box 10)
  - Education 157x, Course Materials (Box 10)
  - Education 165x, Course Materials (Box 10)
  - Education 165, Course Materials and Evaluations (Box 10)
  - Report: The Needs of Public Schools, April 1948 (Box 10)
  - Union Gap Investigation, Yakima 1952 (Box 10)
  - Evanston TWP High School (Box 10)
  - Toppenish School District General Faculty Meeting Notes, 1942-1943 (Box 10)
  - Toppenish School District Secondary Faculty Meeting Notes, 1942-1943 (Box 10)
  - Toppenish School District Committee Notes, 1942-1943 (Box 10)
  - Toppenish School District Faculty Forum, 1942-1943 (Box 10)
  - N 23 1944 (Box 11)
  - Pa-Ph 25 1944 (Box 11)
  - Pi-Pz 26 1944 (Box 11)
  - Recommendations 1944 (Box 11)
  - Ro-Rz 29 1944 (Box 11)
  - Se-Sm 31 1944 (Box 11)
  - Sn-Sth 32 1944 (Box 11)
  - Sti-Sz 33 1944 (Box 11)
  - T 34 1944 (Box 11)
  - V 35 1944 (Box 11)
  - Wa-Wg 37 1944 (Box 11)
  - War Emergency Certification 1944 (Box 11)
  - Wh-Wz 38 1944 (Box 11)
  - U.G. Whiffen – Correspondence 1944 (Box 11)
  - Agriculture Education – Webb 1945 (Box 11)
  - Aiken – Placement Bureau 1945 (Box 11)
  - Misc. Announcements 1945 (Box 11)
  - Applications Chisholms Job 1945 (Box 11)
  - Applicants to Sch. of Education 1945 (Box 11)
  - Applications for Scho of Ed. Position (general) 1945 (Box 11)
  - A 1 1945 (Box 11)
  - Ba-Be 2 1945 (Box 11)
  - Bi-Bri 3 1945 (Box 11)
  - Bro-By 4 1945 (Box 11)
  - Bryden 1945 (Box 11)
  - Ca-Cl 5 1945 (Box 11)
  - Co-Cy 6 1945 (Box 11)
  - College Post War Adjustment Plans 1944 (Box 11)
  - President Compton and Staff 1945 (Box 11)
  - D 7 1945 (Box 11)
  - Departmental – Reports, Notices 1945 (Box 11)
  - E 8 1945 (Box 11)
  - F 9 1945 (Box 11)
  - Faculty Notices 1945 (Box 11)
  - Fellowships 1945 (Box 11)
  - Future of the College 1943-1944 (Box 11)
  - Speeches 1942-43 (Box 11)
  - Ga-Gl 10 1945 (Box 11)
  - Virgil Geiger 1945 (Box 11)
  - General College Extension 1945 (Box 11)
  - Go-Gy 11 1945 (Box 11)
  - Graduate School 1945 (Box 11)
  - Ha-Hd 12 1945 (Box 11)
  - He-Hi 13 1945 (Box 11)
  - E.O. Holland Correspondence 1945 (Box 11)
  - I 15 1945 (Box 11)
  - Inquiries 1945 (Box 11)
  - J 16 1945 (Box 11)
  - Junior College Committee 1945 (Box 11)
  - K 17 1945 (Box 11)
  - La-Le 18 1945 (Box 11)
  - Li-Ly 19 1945 (Box 11)
  - Library 1945 (Box 11)
  - Ma-Me 2 1945 (Box 11)
  - Me-Mi 21 1945 (Box 11)
  - Meetings Attended 1945 (Box 11)
  - Ma-My 22 1945 (Box 11)
  - N 23 1945 (Box 11)
  - National Education Association and Various Depts 1945 (Box 11)
  - Dean Lee 1945 (Box 11)
  - O 24 1945 (Box 11)
  - Pa-Pe 25 1945 (Box 11)
  - Pamphlets – Misc – Bulletins 1945 (Box 11)
  - Pi-Py 26 1945 (Box 11)
  - Post War Problems 1942 (Box 11)
  - Rg-Ri 28 1945 (Box 11)
  - Committee on Recodefication 1944 (Box 11)
  - Recodification – Cleveland 1944 (Box 11)
  - Recommendations 1945 (Box 11)
  - Registrar 1945 (Box 11)
  - Ro-Ry 29 1945 (Box 11)
  - Salary and Wages 1945 (Box 11)
  - Schedule 1944-1945 (Box 11)
  - Sa-Se 30 1945 (Box 11)
  - Se-Sm 31 1945 (Box 11)
  - Second Semester File 1945 (Box 11)
  - Collage Senate 1945 (Box 11)
  - Sn-Ste 32 1945 (Box 11)
  - State Board 1945 (Box 11)
  - State Board 1945 (Box 11)
  - State Dept. of Education 1945 (Box 11)
  - Sti-Sy 33 1945 (Box 11)
  - T 34 1945 (Box 11)
  - Statistics – General 1945 (Box 11)
  - Travel Authorizations and Vouchers 1945 (Box 11)
  - U 35 1945 (Box 11)
  - U.S. Office of Education 1945 (Box 11)
  - V 36 1946 (Box 11)
  - Vocational, Agric. Education State Dept. 1945 (Box 11)
  - Wa-We 37 1945 (Box 11)
  - Wh-Wy 38 1945 (Box 12)
  - Whiffon – I.A. 1946 (Box 12)
  - Y 39 (No Year) (Box 12)